it's all good afternoon everybody
这一切， 大家下午好
welcome good to see you and welcome to
欢迎很高兴见到你，欢迎 到
all those who are watching on videotape
所有这些谁正在看 录像带
as well I want to clear up I realized
还有我想澄清 ，我意识到
after the last lecture that I didn't
最后 的 演讲后，我没有
explain the idea of peak memory
解释 的峰值内存 的想法
utilization very well to you so I want
利用得非常好给你，所以我想
to just explain that it's an important
只是解释 说，这是一个重要的
idea and I want to make sure that that
想法，我想请确保
we have it clear so if you recall recall
我们必须清楚 ，如果你还记得这么召回
from we have we're executing a series a
从我们有我们执行的一系列
sequence of requests R 0 R 1 R 2 R K up
请求，R 0 R 1个R 2 RK向上的序列
to our n minus 1 and at at any point in
我们n减1，并在在任何点
time after K 1 k plus 1 requests we have
之后的时间K 1 k加 1级 的要求，我们 有
h K which is the the heap size
ħķ这是堆大小
after K plus-1 requests then we have an
k加1后的请求，然后我们有一个
e K which is the aggregate the the sum
Ëķ其是聚合的总和
of all of the payloads after k plus 1
所有 k加1 后的有效载荷的
requests okay so what we're trying to do
申请好了，所以我们现在要做的
with this this PK measure this aggregate
这种这场PK测量这个总
payload is at any point in time so as we
有效载荷是在任何时间点，以便我们
as we execute requests one after the
当我们执行 后的一个请求
other the sum of all the payloads in the
在所有有效载荷的其他总和
heap is going to increase or decrease
堆将会增加或减少
right so if we execute a and allocate
右所以如果我们执行与分配
then this the size of the payloads will
那么有效载荷的这个规模将
increase if we execute a free the size
增加，如果我们执行一个免费大小
of all those allocated payloads will
所有这些分配的有效载荷将
decrease right so so as we're executing
减少右所以这样我们在 执行
this the sequence of requests these the
这些请求在这个序列
aggregate the sum of all the payloads is
聚集所有有效载荷的总和
going to be increasing and decreasing
将要增加和减少
okay and so what we're what we're
好吧 还等什么我们是什么我们
capturing with the sum of all these
与所有这些的总和捕捉
payloads it's like a perfect allocator
有效载荷它就像一个完美的分配器
that has no overheads and and even more
有没有开销 ，甚至更多
so one that we can where we're allowed
这样一个我们可以 在那里我们允许
to compact blocks so the sum of all of
紧凑的块 ，这样所有的总和
the the payloads is the minimum possible
该有效负载是最小的 可能
heap size or it's the minimum possible
堆大小或它的最小可能
number of bytes required by those
这些所需 的字节数
allocated blocks okay so it's very very
分配的块好了，这是非常非常
aggressive and it's impossible to
进取，这是不可能 的
achieve but we're going to use that as
实现但我们要使用它作为
sort of our best case okay and so to
排序我们最好的情况很好，而且这么
measure a peak
衡量一个高峰
Piku memory utilization after K plus-1
k加1后皮裤内存利用率
requests which will denote U of K that's
请求将表示的Kü这
going to be equal to the max for all I
要等于最大 所有我
less than or equal to K
小于或等于 K
of our aggregate payloads divided by the
我们的总有效载荷的除以
size of the heap after after K plus-1
堆的大小为K加1之后后
requests okay so what what we're doing
申请好了，所以我们正在做的事情是什么
with this knack is we're remembering the
这个诀窍是我们想起了
high-water mark you know as our as our
你知道作为 我们的高 水位标记 我们
aggregate payloads increase and decrease
总有效载荷的增加 和减少
we're remembering the high-water mark
我们要记住的 高水位标记
right so that was sort of the worst that
右所以这是那种最糟糕的是
was like the biggest set of payloads
就像最大的集有效载荷
that we had and then so the max is
我们不得不然后让max为
remembering its Ramez remembering that
记住其Ramez记住
high-water mark and then we're dividing
高水位标记，然后我们将
by the total size of the heap in order
通过堆，以便总大小
to get an efficiency measure okay so so
得到一个效率的措施好了，所以
this max DK is kind of this is the best
这个最大DK 是怎么样的，这是 最好的
we could have done divided by the total
我们可以做 的除以总
the total heap size okay so yes
总堆大小好了，所以是
well the allocator keeps track of of how
以及分配器跟踪如何
big the heap is so that's pretty easy
大堆是，这样是很容易
right so it's every time it every time
右所以它的每一次每一次
it does every time it calls s break it's
它 每次通话时间s打破它
just that that adds to the size of the
只是这增加的大小
heap and remember we're we're assuming
堆并记住 我们是我们假设
that the heat in this case is always
在这种情况下，热量总是
increasing okay so but even if even if
还好增加左右，但即使 即使
we allow the heap size to decrease could
我们允许堆大小，以减少可能
just if the allocator is controlling the
只是，如果分配器被控制
size of the heap by calls to s break
通过调用分手吧堆的大小
okay so is that clear
好了，所以是明确
so for UK the higher the better okay and
所以英国越高越好很好，而且
for any sequence of allocates and freeze
对于分配和冻结的任何序列
this max PK will be the same okay that's
这个最大的PK将是相同的还好这
constant right
恒权
but what varies is H of K and that
但什么变化为K，并使得 h
depends on how efficient your your
取决于如何有效地你的
allocator is is using the heap storage
分配器被使用堆存储
okay
好的
yes question so what we're doing is at
是的 问题，所以我们正在做的事情是在
any point in time after after k plus 1
后k加 1 之后的任何时间点
requests we're about we're evaluating
我们对我们正在评估申请
the utilization of our heap up till that
我们堆起来到那的利用率
point so it should be k 4i i less than
点，从而它应当在 K 4I我小于
or equal to k oh i'm sorry
或等于 k哦， 我很抱歉
yeah sorry good good catch that should
噢，抱歉好福气应该
be an eye right we want to look at all
是我们要考虑所有的眼睛权
the all the for all the requests that
所有的所有请求，即
came before okay any other questions
以前 还好任何其他问题 来了
okay
好的
all right so last time we looked at some
没事所以 我们 最后 一次 看了一些
simple the basics of dynamic storage
动态存储的简单的基础知识
allocation a we're going to look at some
分配的，我们要 看看一些
more sophisticated techniques using
使用更复杂的技术
different data structures to store the
不同的数据结构 来存储
free list primarily we'll look at
免费名单主要是我们来看看
implicit allocators so we'll get a sort
隐式分配器，所以我们会得到 一个排序
of a brief survey of how garbage
如何垃圾的简短调查
collectors work and we'll just look at
收藏家工作，我们就来看看
one just just one very simple kind of
一个才刚刚一个很简单的那种
garbage collector but it'll give you an
垃圾收集器，但它会给你一个
idea of what that means and then we'll
中 这意味着 什么想法，然后我们会
finish up we'll finish up by looking at
完成了，我们将通过观察完成了
it at all the ways you can get yourself
它你可以让自己的所有方法
into trouble by using dynamically
成通过使用动态 麻烦
allocated storage so once once you once
分配存储所以一旦当你 一次
you use once you start dynamically
你用你一旦开始动态
allocating storage things can go really
分配存储的东西可以去真的
bad really quickly and so we'll go over
坏真的 很快，所以我们就去了
some of those some of those bad things
一些 那些其中 的一些不好的东西
that can happen and try to alert you to
这可能发生 ，尽量提醒 您
those so you don't do them in your
那些让你不这样做他们在你
programs
程式
okay so we looked at how to store a free
好了，所以我们看到了如何 存储免费
look free list in this sort of implicit
看在这种隐含的空闲列表
form by just walking the entire heat and
形式由刚会走路的 整个热和
and thereby sort of being able to visit
从而那种能够访问
all the free blocks but we can do better
所有的空闲块，但我们可以做的更好
if we actually have a doubly if we store
如果我们实际上有一个 双重如果我们存储
the free bought the free list is using
自由买了免费列表 使用
as a doubly linked list so in we call
作为一个双向链表所以我们称之为
these explicit free lists so the idea
这些明确的空闲列表这样的想法
with an explicit free list is that we
有一个明确的空闲列表是我们
put pointers we put the pointers that
put指针我们把该指针
implement this the doubly linked list
实现这种双向链表
inside the the body of a free block
空闲块 的主体内
where the old payload used to go so
其中使用的旧的有效载荷去这样
allocated blocks look exactly the same
分配的块长得一模一样
as they did the floor right there's a
因为他们没有右边地板有一个
header boundary tag optional boundary
头边界标签可选边界
tag splitter and then this the payload
标签分离器，然后该有效载荷
and any padding free blocks though the
和任何填充空闲块虽然
allocated and the allocator is not
分配 和分配不
allowed to touch anything in the inside
允许在里面碰任何东西
the the payload of an allocated block
所分配的块的有效载荷
but free blocks are free right nobody's
但空闲数据块的自由权的人
using them and so we the allocator can
使用它们，所以我们的分配器可以
put the pointers that implement the data
把实现数据的指针
structure inside the what was the old
里面有什么是旧体制
payload so logically this is just a
有效载荷所以逻辑上这只是一个
simple doubly linked list that you've
你已经简单的双向链表
all seen before but actually these
之前，但实际上这些都见过
things can be anywhere in memory right
东西都可以在内存中的任何地方的权利
and so you know here we have we have a
所以你知道这里，我们有我们有一个
block of size six and it has a forward
大小的 6 块 ，它有一个向前
pointer that points to some other link
指针指向一些其他链接
and it has a backwards pointer that
它有一个向后指针
points to this block which happens to be
指向该块恰好是
have a greater memory address than than
比大于 a的内存地址
it okay so just the idea is you can't
它好了，只是这个想法是，你不能
you know unless unless you make unless
你知道，除非，除非你做，除非
you go to great pains to maintain this
你去不厌其烦地保持这种
sort of address ordered structure these
排序这些地址有序结构
these these blocks can be sort of
这些， 这些模块是那种
scattered anywhere in memory oh yeah so
分散在存储器中的任何噢等等
this is after several you know just sort
这是 经过数你知道 刚才排序
of indefinite number of Malik's and
马利克的不定数，
fries and yes oh yeah good question it's
薯条是的哦，是 很好的 问题，这是
like so the question is what would
像这样的问题是什么会
happen if you free to a block that was
如果你免费这是一个块发生
in between two free blocks and so you
在 两者 之间 自由块，所以你
have to coalesce it gets a little tricky
要合并就有点棘手
and I'll show you in a second good now
我会在第二个好，现在告诉你
allocating oh yes questions so the
分配哦，是这样的问题了
question is what happens with locality
问题是当地发生了什么
so you still get you still get block
所以你仍然可以得到你仍然得到块
locality you know use blocks are still
地方你知道使用的块仍
contiguous so if but if if you're
连续的，所以如果，但如果如果你
scanning sort of a set of allocated
扫描类型的一组分配的
blocks it would be better if you could
块，如果你能会更好
keep them all contiguous right that so
让他们所有连续正确的，所以
it's really and so there's a you know
它真的等有一个你知道的
that's a trade-off I don't it gets
这是一个权衡，我不它得到
difficult if you think how can you
困难，如果你觉得你怎么能
maintain so you don't really care about
保持这样你就不会真正关心
the locality of free blocks right you're
空闲块的局部性权你
just walking a linked list well no I
只是走一个 链表 以及无我
shouldn't say that that's if you're
不应该说 ，这就是如果你
walking that list if you hit one one
走该列表，如果你打一个一个
free block it would it would bring in a
空闲块会它将把在
whole page so it'd be better if you were
整个页面所以它会更好，如果你是
walking if the list you know if as much
如果 走 在列表中，您知道，如果尽可能多
of that list was contained within that
该名单载内
page so even that so you would benefit
页面所以即使 是这样，你将受益
you could benefit with both allocated
你可以用两种分配中受益
blocks because applications would be
块，因为应用程序会
using them and with free blocks because
使用它们，并与自由块，因为
the allocator would be walking that that
分配器将走的是那
free list so question
免费列表，以便问题
we could make sense to have a program
我们可以做 的意义有一个程序
that effectively energy to a pre break
能够有效 能量的预断
so even though they only need two even
因此，即使他们 只需要两个甚至
though they only alkane into a couple of
虽然他们只烷烃成情侣
mono sir if you know in the future
单先生，如果你将来知道
mentality at Domino them somehow the
多米诺 他们 的心态 不知何故
alkanes are they we're going to try to
烷烃是他们 ，我们要尝试
you can help you knowledge about it work
你可以帮助你了解一下工作
that's a really good question so the
这是一个非常好的问题 ，因此
question is could would it be possible
问题是 ， 可能将有可能
for an application to sort of give hints
对于应用程序之类的给提示
to the allocator that would increase
该分配器 会增加
them improve the allocators performance
他们提高分配器性能
or memory utilization the the answer you
或内存利用率的答案你
absolutely could but it's if you did it
绝对可以，但如果你做到了这
wouldn't be a general-purpose allocator
不会是一个通用的分配器
so like malloc it's a general-purpose
所以喜欢 的malloc 它是一个通用
allocator so it and it provides no
分配器所以它和它没有提供
there's no option it doesn't provide any
没有选择它不提供任何
arguments in its interface for passing
在其界面传递参数
that information in but it absolutely if
在但它绝对如果 信息
it had some knowledge about the future
它有对未来的一些知识
behavior of a program that could benefit
程序的行为可能会受益
right so especially I consider you
右所以特别我认为你
always have this decision when you place
总是有这样的决定，当你把
an allocated block whether to split that
一个分配的块是否分割该
block or not well if you knew that you
阻止或没有得到很好的，如果你知道你
were going to get a request you know for
打算让你知道的请求
if you split that block and you knew
如果拆分块，你就知道
that you're going to give requests
你打算 给 请求
coming in the future first for sizes of
在未来即将到来的第一个 尺寸
the original block then you wouldn't
原来的块，那么你就不会
want to split it because then you would
想拆它，因为那时你会
want it you would just keep it unsplit
希望你只是保持 不分开
and then when you freed it then you'd
然后当你释放它，那么你会
have a block that would be the right
有这 将是合适的块
size for that that future request and so
尺寸为将来的要求等
it's you can absolutely benefit from
这是你绝对 可以 从中受益
that and so although you can't if
这一点，所以虽然你不能，如果
general-purpose allocators there's no
通用内存分配器没有
provision for that kind of hinting but
计提的那种 暗示的，但
there's nothing to prevent an alligator
没有什么可以防止鳄鱼
from doing predictions based on the the
从基础上的做预测
previous pattern of requests you know so
请求以前的模式，你知道，所以
if you're getting a pattern of requests
如果你得到的请求模式
it's alternating large block small block
它交替大块小块
large box small block you could you
大箱小块状你可能在你
could exploit that maybe maybe predict
可以利用，也许，也许预测
that the next request will be for a you
那下一个请求将 是 一个你
know it it's the previous request is for
知道这是以前的请求是
a large block the next one might be for
大块的下一个可能是
a small block and you could
一个小方块，你可以
that's a good question any other
这是一个很好的问题， 任何其他
questions wizard yep
问题向导是的
I don't know I so the question is other
我不知道我这样的问题是其他
are there intelligent alligators that do
是有智能 的短吻鳄是 做
that kind of prediction and if there are
那种 如果有 预测 和
I don't know of them but I wouldn't I
我不知道他们的，但我不会我
wouldn't say no yes question what would
不会说没有问题是会 是什么
happen you end up with a free buck up a
发生你 结束了一个免费的 降压了
block just like it's just a single block
块就像它只是一个单独的块
oh so the question is what if you ended
哦， 所以问题 是，如果你什么结束
up with a free block that's a single
了 一个空闲块，这是 一个单
block surrounded by two allocated blocks
块由两个分配块包围
well in fact I mean that's one of the
好其实我的意思是这的一个
invariants that a good alligator has to
一个良好的鳄鱼 有不变量
maintain you should never have two
保持你永远不应该有两个
contiguous free blocks right the
连续的自由块右边的
alligator should always be coalescing as
鳄鱼应始终作为合并
much as it can and if it if it does that
尽可能它可以，如果它，如果它确实是
coalescing is it it always does that
凝聚是它总是这样说
coalescing then then there will never be
凝聚然后再永远不会有
two contiguous free blocks okay
两个连续的自由块行
yes a question oh you'll see when we it
是个问题 哦，你会看到，当我们这
comes into play when we free a block
进场时 ，我们释放一个块
because you have to sort of stitch up
因为你要排序的缝合起来
when you free a block you have to sort
当你释放一个块， 你必须 排序
of stitch up the the linked list and so
的缝合起来的链表 等
you need both you need both pointers you
你既需要你既需要你的指针
can do it with singly linked list so in
可以用单链表所以在做
your in the knr book there's a an
您 在 书中KNR有一个一
alligator that uses a singly linked list
使用单链表鳄鱼
but the the disadvantages that free
但缺点是免费的
requires a search so it requires a
需要一个搜索，它需要一个
search from the beginning of the list to
从列表的开头进行搜索
find the previous block
找到 以前 的 块
and there are questions these are good
并有问题，这些都 不错
yes question okay so the question is for
是的问题好了，所以这个问题 是
memory utilization how does the header
内存利用率如何做头
and footer count towards memory
和对内存页脚计数
utilization and so those those are
利用等等这些那些
overhead that decrease memory
开销减少内存
utilization okay because they're not
利用没关系，因为他们不
payload so when we were computing memory
有效载荷所以当我们计算内存
utilization we're doing it by we're
利用我们正在做的我们
using the payload the aggregate payload
使用有效载荷的有效载荷聚合
to to to estimate our utilization or to
对估计 我们的利用率 还是
compute our utilization so anything
计算我们的利用率，所以，只要
that's not payload SAR is is overhead
这不是有效载荷SAR是一定的开销
one word and everything like okay was
一个字， 一切都 像 没事了
also one word so we had if all of our
也一个字，所以我们不得不如果我们所有的
payloads were one word and our overhead
有效载荷有一个字，我们的开销
was was one word then there'd be 50%
是为一个字那么会是50％
yes if you have to book this point into
是的，如果你要预订这点成
the next and previously glossy Sony
下一个和以前 有光泽索尼
like whatever like every time yeah so
喜欢什么样每次都这样呀
the question is do you still need a
问题是，你还 需要一个
boundary tag if you have these these
边界标签，如果你有这些这些
next and previous pointers and the
下一个和以前的指针和
answer is yes absolutely and you'll see
答案是肯定的绝对，你会看到
in a second why yes okay that's a really
在第二，为什么是好的，这是一个真正的
good question so you know what do you do
很好的问题，所以 你知道你该怎么办
if you have next and previous pointers
如果你有一个和前一个指针
what happens if there's a request for a
如果有一个请求会发生什么
smaller a smaller block so the answer is
小的更小的块所以答案 是
that all of those things the header the
所有 的这些 东西头的
footer the next and previous pointers
页脚中的一个和前一个指针
impose a minimum block size so if you
并处以 最小的块大小，所以如果你
have a one-word header one-word footer
有一个字的头一个字页脚
one word pre even one word next then
一个字，甚至前一个字旁则
you're your minimum block sizes is four
你是你的最低块大小 为 四个
bytes and that would be with a zero of
字节，这将是一个零
zero size payload so you can never
零大小的有效载荷，所以你永远不能
allocate a block smaller than your
分配一块比你小
minimum block size so that's a very good
最小的块大小所以这是一个非常 好的
very good question so it makes a
非常好的问题所以它是一个
difference right even though even though
差异右即使即使
we're you know it looks like we're
我们要知道它看起来我们
getting these it looks like we're
让这些看起来 我们
getting these pointers here for free but
及彼这些指针 免费的 ，但
we're not really because of this minimum
我们并不是真的因为 这个最小 的
block size requirement yep there we go
块大小需求 是的，我们继续
or allocated gigantic luckily for self
或分配给自己巨大的幸运
to give you specific different parts of
给你具体的不同部分
that because they say one day when I'll
因为他们说 ， 有 一天我会
get on a truck analogy since I don't
坐上卡车的比喻，因为我不
refresh my page or it's one space so
刷新我的网页，或者是一个空间，以便
right but if you want to like take first
正确的 ，但如果你要 喜欢拿第一
half make them drugs take Technic and a
一半让他们 采取药物 和TECHNIC一
certain something and if we say all of
某些东西，如果说所有 的
this up my program ridiculous like so
这件事我的程序可笑 ， 像 这样
it's like your movie option for that one
它就 像是 一个 电影的选择
which I get Nick bakas wake up yeah okay
这是我得到尼克·巴卡斯 醒来好耶
so the question is can you just get a
所以，问题是你可以得到一个
get one large block and then split it up
得到一个大的块，然后把它分解了
and I guess you're assuming that the
我想你是假设
requests would be four equally sized
请求将 四个同样大小的
objects right so this and and that's a
对象权利，使这一点，这就是一个
really good strategy actually so if you
真正好的战略其实所以如果你
if you know or if you think that your
如果你知道，或者如果你认为你的
workload is going to have no you can't
工作量都将有没有你
do this in general-purpose allocators
在 通用分配器做到这一点
but for like a special-purpose allocator
但对于像专用分配器
if you know that you're going to be
如果你知道你将要
asking for objects that are all the same
要求 是所有相同的 对象
size like compilers for example make
大小一样的编译器，例如化妆
maintain abstract syntax trees and
维护抽象语法树
they're allocating nodes dynamically and
他们是动态分配的节点和
those nodes are the same size so if you
这些节点的大小相同，所以如果你
can you can exploit that by just
你可以可以利用由刚
allocating a large chunk and then
分配大块，然后
allocating all the objects of that size
分配该尺寸 的所有对象
out of that chunk it's very efficient
出该块它的效率非常高
you don't even need pointers or anything
你甚至不需要指针或什么
all you need is a bit vector to tell you
你需要的是一个位向量来告诉你
which chunks are allocated in which
该块被分配在
chunks are free and then and you also as
块是免费的，那么， 你也可以作为
a side-effect you'll get that contiguous
副作用您将获得连续
that contiguous access so if a program
该连续访问，以便如果一个程序
access those those objects like to be
这些访问这些对象喜欢被
part of a linked list there was
链表的一部分有
something that it was going to traverse
这是要穿越的东西
you could allocate those in order and
你可以为了分配这些和
contiguously
连续
now with with a general-purpose
现在用通用
allocator where you don't really know
分配器，你真的不知道
what's going to be requested it's
什么会被要求 它的
ASL is a sector insulting absolutely you
ASL是扇区侮辱 绝对是你
could do that you can make general
能做到这一点，你可以让一般
assumptions about the sort of behavior
对那种行为的假设
of your programs and you know you could
你的程序的，你知道 你可以
you could run traces or like in the case
你可以运行痕迹或在案件喜欢
of malok lab you could look at the
malok实验室，你可以看看
traces but that's no that's a really
痕迹，但是这是没有，这是一个真正的
good thing you know you can't you're you
你知道好东西你不能 你是你
can't just like do if statements to say
不能只是喜欢做，如果声明说
well if the size is 42 and then the next
以及如果尺寸是42，然后 下一个
size is 24 then I know it's this trace
尺寸是24后来我知道这是该 跟踪
okay but you can look at a trace and say
不错，但你可以看看跟踪并说
there's an interesting pattern here I'm
这里有一个有趣的模式 ，我
going to account for that pattern I'm
要 解释这个模式我
going to optimize for that pattern and
要优化该模式 和
that that would just and that's
，这将只是，这就是
perfectly valid that's just like taking
完全有效的，这只是像回吐
advantage of your workload right that's
利用你的工作量正确的是
what we do in systems all the time yeah
我们做什么，在系统中所有的时间耶
can we divided up our data which is
我们可以瓜分我们的数据是
stored in some other party
存储 在其他 方
Oh Oh so the question is why can't we
哦，哦，这样的 问题是，为什么我们不能
why can't we sort of have separate areas
我们为什么不能排序的具有独立区域
of the heap for the pointers and the
堆的指针和的
payloads all right join them up with
有效载荷没事加入他们了
pointers oh why not
三分球哦，为什么不
okay so the question is why not why
好了， 问题 是为什么不 为什么
can't we split up payloads and link them
我们不能分裂的有效载荷并将其链接
together with pointers the answer is
与指针一起答案
that the applications expecting a
这些应用程序期待
contiguous block you can't allocate or
连续块不能分配或
can't put anything in the payload it all
不能把任何东西在有效载荷一切
I can do all it's allowed to do is
我可以做所有它允许做的是
return a contiguous block of the size of
返回 的大小的 连续块
the application requested and after once
应用程序请求后一次
it does that it can't touch it okay all
它，它不能触摸它 好一切
right good good all right so let's look
好一个好没事所以让我们看看
at how we'd allocate and free once if we
怎么我们会分配和释放一次，如果我们
have this this explicit list how we
有这个这个明确的清单，我们怎么样
would allocate and free block so
将分配和释放块，
allocating is pretty simple we'll have
分配是相当简单的，我们将有
so here's our sort of a graphic of our
所以这里是我们的图形中 我们的排序
free list so we have forward pointers
空闲列表所以我们必须 前进指针
and backward pointers and the idea is we
落后指针和想法是我们
want to allocate out of this middle
要分配出这个中间
block so we allocate the block of the
块，所以我们分配的块
size that we need and then we just
大小， 我们需要，然后 我们就
update the forward and back pointers of
更新的前进和后退指针
the previous and next blocks to point to
上一页和下一页块指向
this new free block okay so that's
这种新的空闲块好了，这就是
pretty simple we're just we're updating
很简单，我们 只是我们要更新
one two three four five six six pointers
一二三四五六六指针
okay now give us it gets trickier when
现在没事给我们它变得棘手时
we have to free because because we
我们不得不因为自由，因为我们
require coalescing so when you free a
需要凝聚所以当你释放一个
block that that was previously allocated
阻止先前被分配
the question is what do you do with that
问题是你怎么与做
free block right it wasn't in the free
空闲块右它不是在免费
list because it was an allocated block
列表中，因为它是一个分配的块
so now that you've freed the block where
所以现在你已经释放了其中块
do you put it as you've got to put it
你把它当成你得把它
somewhere so that the simplest thing is
某个地方， 这样 最简单 的 事情是
this life--all policy so the simplest
这样的生活 - 所有的策略，以最简单的
thing is just put it at the beginning of
事情只是把它之初
the list so the last block freed is the
列表，以便释放了最后一块是
first block allocated if it's it's okay
如果这是它的好第一个块分配
so that's so-called like oh now this is
所以这所谓的喜欢哦，现在这 是
simple because you're always doing the
简单，因为你总是在做
same thing you're just putting the block
同样的事情 ， 你 只是把 块
at the beginning the list and it's
在开始列表，它是
constant time you're just updating a few
恒定的时间你只是更新了数
pointers okay but the study suggests
指针不错 ，但研究 表明，
that the the fragmentation can be worse
该碎片可能会更糟
than the alternative technique which is
比其他技术，该技术
to keep the blocks ordered by address
继续按地址排列块
okay so when uh if you if you if you
好了，所以当 呃，如果你，如果你，如果 你
choose this address ordered policy when
选择这个地址下单策略
you when you free an allocated block
您在释放一个分配的块
you're going to somehow figure out
你会以 某种方式弄清楚
you're going to somehow place that block
你会以某种方式把该块
in the list so that the previous block
在列表中， 前块
begins at a smaller address and the next
开始于一个较小的地址和下
block begins at a larger address right
块开始于更大的地址 右
so this generally involves some kind of
所以这通常涉及某种
search right you don't you're just given
搜索对你没有，你只是给
this allocated block and then somehow
这种分配的块，然后以某种方式
you've got and you know its address and
你有，你知道它的地址和
so now you've got to somehow search the
所以现在你必须以某种方式搜索
the free list to find the you know the
空闲列表找到你知道
proper place to insert it now I suppose
适当的地方插入，现在我想
you could do better if you had some kind
你可以做的 更好，如果你有某种
of so if you could speed up that search
所以如果你能加快该搜索
with some kind of balance tree that
与某种平衡树的该
would be one option right but then that
将是一个 选择 权，但那时，
the problem we always run into with
我们总会遇到这样的问题
balance trees and usually is one student
平衡树，通常是一个学生
at lea somebody always tries to
在LEA有人 总是试图
implement malloc with a some kind of
实现的malloc有某种
balance tree red-black tree or something
平衡树 红黑树什么的
and it seems like a really good idea but
它似乎是一个 很好的主意，但
you have to realize that you're you're
你必须 认识到 ，你是你
competing with with other techniques
与其他技术竞争
specifically segregated lists that are
特别是隔离的名单是
very fast and have very small constant
速度非常快，并且具有非常小的常数
factors and there's even though even
因素和存在的，即使连
though ordered lists are I think it's
虽然有序列表是我认为这是
usually n log in to update an order tree
通常N日志中更新的顺序树
upon your ordered tree that constant
在你所订购之树常
factors can be can be quite large and so
因素可能会 很大， 因此
usually get nailed up with the constant
通常会得到钉了恒
factors of maintaining the tree and you
保持树的因素，你
don't get help that the search time is
没有得到帮助，搜索时间
log n but as we'll see with segregated
日志N但是我们会看到隔离
lists in the in the limit as in the
在 列出的限制 作为
limit as the number of different size
限制如 不同尺寸的数
classes increases the the search time
类增加了搜索时间
approaches constant time and if you if
接近恒定的时间，如果你，如果
you have size classes that cover ranges
你有大小类，覆盖范围
of powers of two then the search time
两 周搜索时间的权力
reduces to a long time anyway because
减少了很长一段时间，因为反正
the the size of each classes are now
每个班级的大小是现在
logarithmic the log so you know I would
对数日志，所以你 知道我会
suggest done you know just doing a
建议做了你知道刚才做 了
simple thing usually whenever you're
简单的事情通常每当 你
you're dealt with sort of large design
你处理了几分大设计
space like malakut you're better off
像malakut空间，你最好
doing the simple thing and then
做简单的事情，然后
optimizing only when you see that
只有当你看到优化
there's that you need to optimize okay
还有，你需要优化好
so remember last time we talked about
所以记得我们谈到了最后一次
this trick to to eliminate the boundary
这一招消除 边界
tag footer and allocated blocks that's
标签页脚和分配的块这
an example of an optimization you should
优化的例子，你应该
defer so that wait you know wait get do
推迟让等待 你知道 等待得到做
the simple thing and then try to improve
简单的事情，然后尝试改善
incrementally by int by you know there's
通过逐步由INT你知道 有
just this optimization or another
只是这种优化或其他
optimization so there's this phenomena
优化所以有此现象
of a lot of lot of programmers make a
很多很多程序员的使
mistake of what we call premature
就是我们所说的过早错误
optimization so try to think of all the
优化所以尽量 想的一切
fancy things they can do and then they
花哨的东西，他们可以做什么，然后他们
put all those in at the beginning and
把所有这些在开始 和
before they even know that it needs to
之前，他们甚至不知道它需要
be optimized
进行优化
okay so D so the way you want to work on
好吧，D， 使得你想要的方式 去努力
this and any any sort of complex problem
这一点，任何种类的任何复杂的问题 的
like like an alligator is to you know
像鳄鱼般的是，你知道
first do fairly simple things and then
首先做相当简单的事情，然后
look and see where where the slowdowns
看看，看看哪里哪里怠工
are inefficiencies are and then just
是效率低下，然后就
sort of
有点
hit those one after the other and
打击的一前一后和
optimize only for the things that are
只有优化那些事
necessary and this is a good example of
必要的，这 是一个很好的例子
that okay now to get to your question
现在好了去你的问题
about freeing freeing is tough because
关于释放释放是艰难的，因为
we always have to do this coalescing
我们总是不得不这样做凝聚
right because of this invariant that we
正确的，因为这个不变的是我们
can never have to free blocks to
可从来没有自由块
adjacent free blocks so let's go through
相邻空闲块，以便让我们通过
each of those four cases that we went
每一个这四个案例，我们去
over last time and see how we would do
比去年 时间，看看 我们 会 怎么 做
it now that we have this just this
现在， 我们有这个只是 这个
explicit free list so here we have the
明确免费列表，在这里我们有
root of our free list pointing to the
我们的指向空闲列表的根
first block in the free list there's a
在免费榜第一块有一个
null back pointer and then that there's
空回指针，那么有
a null pre pointer and then the next
空预指针再 下一
next pointer points to some unspecified
接下来的指针指向某个不确定的
block and so we have this yellow block
块，所以我们有这样的黄色块
which is allocated and now the
被分配到现在的
application is called free free with a
应用程序 被称为自由免费 使用
pointer that points the beginning of
指针指向的开始
this block so what do we do well this
该块所以我们做什么以及这
case is pretty simple because there's no
情况是非常简单的 ，因为没有
coalescing because both the predecessor
合并，因为两者的前身
and successor blocks are are allocated
和后继块分配
okay so we just this newly freed block
好了，所以我们只是这个新释放的块
now becomes we're going to do a LIFO
现在成为我们要做一个LIFO
policy so this becomes the first block
政策使这成为第一个块
in the free list and so we update the
在免费的列表，所以我们更新
route to point to this this newly freed
路径指向这个这个新 释放
block and we update the forward pointer
阻止我们更新正向指针
of that block to point to what used to
该块的指向什么用
be the first block in the heap
是在堆中的第一个块
now I'm going to be careful it's a
现在我要小心，这是一个
little bit confusing because we've got
有点混乱，因为我们已经有了
sort of two notions of like previous and
有点像以前的两个概念，并
next right there's the you know given
右旁还有的你知道给定
some given some block
一些给予一定的块
there's the predecessor block in memory
有一个在内存中的前身块
which may or may not be allocated or
其可以或可以不被分配或
free right it may or may not be in a
它可能会或可能不会在自由权
free list and there's a successor block
免费列表，并有一个后继块
okay so we'll use predecessor and
好了，所以我们将使用前作
successor to distinguish adjacency in
继任者来区分相邻的
memory okay and we'll use pre even next
内存没关系，我们将使用事先连旁边
to denote adjacency in the free list
表示 在空闲列表 邻接
okay so this this block is the next
好了，所以这此 块是下一个
block for the current block and it has
块用于当前块 ，它有
no previous block okay
没有以前好块
all right now what about case to number
现在好了怎么样 的情况下，以数
case to the predecessor block is free
情况下向前身块空闲
and the successor block is is allocated
和后继块分配
and now we want to free this what was an
现在我们要释放这个东西是一个
allocated block denoted by yellow and we
分配块由黄色和我们记
have this this successor this
有这个这个这个接班人
predecessor block is part of the free
前身块是自由的一部分
list right so it has it has previous and
列表中右键所以它有它 以前和
next blocks that are just part of the
接下来的块是 只是 部分
free list and so our route points to the
免费名单等我们的路线指向
first block in the list and then
在列表中，然后第一块
eventually you get to this free block
最终你得到这个空闲块
which points to this free block which
它指向该自由块，其
points to this free block okay so what
指向这个空闲块好了，所以什么
we have to do then is we have to
我们需要做的就是我们要
coalesce these two these two blocks into
合并这两个这两个块成
one big free block okay and then we have
一个大的空闲块行不行，然后我们有
to splice it out and stick it at the
拼接出来，并在坚持下去
beginning of the list okay so what that
列表中的 开始 好了，这是什么
looks like
看起来像
conceptually is we we we coalesce these
概念 就是我们我们我们这些合并
two blocks now to form this one free
现在两个街区，形成这一个免费
block and then we splice it out by
块，然后我们剪接出来的
having what was the what was its
已经什么是什么是它
previous block now point to what used to
先前块现在都指向什么用
be the next block okay
成为下一个块行不行
fix of the current block okay so this
当前 块 的 修复 好了，所以这
the pointer from this block now points
从该块中的指针现在指向
to this block okay and then the so we've
该块行不行， 然后 使我们已经
effectively spliced that that current
有效拼接认为， 目前的
block out of the free list and then the
块空闲列表，然后将出
root we have the root point to that
根我们有 根点到
block so that's now the new first block
块，使得现在新的第一块
of the list
名单
okay and then we have to update what
好吧，然后我们必须更新什么
used to be the first block in the list
用于在列表中的第一个块
so now it points back to the the newly
所以现在它指向回 新
freed coalesce block so that cleared
释放 聚结块， 使 清
everybody its yep so with the rupiah
大家的没错所以与盾
global variable it could be or it could
全局 变量 可能是， 也可能
be there's there's two ways to do this
是有有两种方法可以做到 这一点
right it could just be a global variable
右它可能只是一个全局变量
or it could be a it could be a struct
或者它可能是一个也可能是一个结构
that of like previous the next pointer
像以前的下一个指针
so sometimes it's easier if you keep the
所以有时候，如果你保持更容易
same you know when you're doing linked
同样的，你知道，当你在做链接
lists that the route if you just make it
列出 了途径，如果你只是使它
the same as all the other nodes it can
同样的，因为它可以在所有其他节点
simplify things but yeah it could be a
简化事情但是，是它可能是一个
global variable global scalar in the
在全局变量全局 标
allocator okay so case oh now one thing
分配好了，所以情况哦，现在有一件事
one thing that comes to mind there is
我想到的还有一件事
like there is an optimization that we
像有一个优化，我们
could do in this case do you see when we
可在这种情况下做的，你看我们什么时候
when we coalesce we could just leave
当我们合并，我们可以见好就收
that block right there in the free list
在免费列表 框右侧 有
right we did although I believe adopted
右我们做虽然 我相信通过
so the examples I'm going to show you
所以我要去的例子来 告诉你
are assuming a LIFO policy for insertion
在假设中插入的LIFO政策
we could just leave it there right that
我们可以先不管它正确的
and just don't update anything just
只是不只是更新任何内容
increase create this newly coalesce
加大创建这个新 合并
block and then mentally we don't require
块，然后精神上 我们不 要求
in this case we wouldn't require any
在这种情况下，我们不需要任何
free list manipulation okay but that
免费列表操作不错，但该
would be that would be one of these
是这将是其中之一
optimizations right
优化权
now case three if you recall is the case
现在案例三，如果你还记得的 话
where the the predecessor block is
其中前身块是
allocated and the successor block is
分配和后继块
freed
释放
the successor block is free so in this
后继块是免费的，所以在这
case what we have to do is we have to
什么情况下，我们要做的是 ， 我们必须
create we have to coalesce the newly
创建我们必须凝聚新
freed block with the with the successor
释放的块与与后继
block and then we have to splice it out
块，然后我们要拼接出来
in just the same way we did in case two
在用同样的 方法 我们做 的情况下，两个
so we splice it out of the the list and
所以我们拼接出来的名单和
then put it at the beginning of the list
然后把它在列表 的开头
by pointing the root at it and then
通过指向 在它 的 根，然后
updating what used to be the first block
更新曾经 被认为是第一个 块
in the list updating its back pointer
在列表中更新其返回指针
it's pre pointer to point to the this
它的前指针指向 这个
newly coalesced block okay so it's this
新合并块好了，所以它的这个
is completely symmetric with the case
是与壳体 完全对称
that we looked at before but now we no
我们看着 面前 的 ，但现在我们没有
longer have it's a little bit trickier
再有它的一点点麻烦
if we just wanted to leave this block in
如果我们只是想离开这个块
the free list we'd have to update all
空闲列表，我们不得不更新所有
these pointers to point back to the
这些指针指向回
beginning of the newly created block
开始新 创建 的块
okay so there's so in this case there's
好了，所以有这么在这种情况下，有
no performance optimization right we're
没有性能优化对，我们
still updating the same number of
还更新了相同数量的
pointers whether we put it in the
指针，我们是否把它放在
beginning of the list or if we if we
开始列表 ， 或者 如果我们如果我们
splice it or if we leave it there
拼接，或者如果我们就此打住
and now case four is the that's the case
而现在的情况下四是那样的话
where both the predecessor and successor
在前任和继任者都
blocks are free so we have to apply the
块是免费的，所以我们必须应用
same slicing technique to both the the
同一分片技术都 意识到
predecessor block and we have to we have
前身块，我们必须我们有
to create this new coalesced block and
创造这个新的 聚结块
then we have to splice we have to we
接下来我们就来拼接，我们必须我们
have to sort of splice it out by
要排序的拼接出来的
updating two different sets of previous
更新两套不同以往
and successor blocks okay so when we
和后继块好了，所以 ， 当 我们
when we're finished with that the this
当我们完成了该本
newly coalesced block now is the first
新合并块，现在是第一
block in the in the heap the four in the
块在堆中的四个
free list and we spliced it we spliced
免费单， 我们剪接我们是持拼接
it out from these two different parts of
从上述 两个 不同的部分出来
the the free list
在空闲列表
okay so any questions about this is this
好了，所以任何相关的问题是这样的
is where you really it looks it looks
是 你真的看起来它 看起来
really simple to do but I guarantee you
很简单的事， 但我向 你 保证
this will be some of the hardest it's
这将是 它的 一些 最困难的
only like 200 lines of code but some of
只有像200 行 代码，但一些
the hardest code you'll have to write
最难的代码，就必须写
because you you're sort of free of the
因为你，你那种 自由的
C's type system you have to do
C'S型系统，您需要做的
everything by explicitly casting these
一切通过明确这些铸造
pointers are just in the middle of
指针只是在中间
arbitrary blocks and so it looks simple
任意块，所以它看起来很简单
with the diagram but you're going to
与图表，但你要
have to be really careful when you do
必须 当你 真 细心
this in fact what I would suggest the
这其实是我 会建议
best suggestion I can give you is it is
最好的建议我 可以给你的是它是
to start with the implicit list
先从 隐含名单
allocator that we describe in the book
分配器，我们在书中 描述
which is too slow to get any credit
这是太慢 获得任何信贷
terrible allocator but it contains all
可怕的分配器，但它包含了所有
the basic ideas and then write function
基本 的想法，然后写函数
write a function called insert block and
写一个函数调用插入块和
write another function called remove
另写函数调用删除
block that inserts a block into the free
块插入块成游离
list and removes a block from the free
列出并从自由删除块
list respectively and if you if you
分别列表， 如果你，如果你
write if you abstract it like that if
写，如果你抽象的像，如果
you use that kind of abstraction it's
您使用的那种 抽象的 它
pretty simple to to convert the implicit
很简单的隐式转换
list allocator to an explicit list
名单分配给一个明确的列表
allocator okay it'll still be too slow
分配好它仍然会是 太慢
to get so then that will go from like an
得到这样的话会从去 像
F allocator to a b- allocator and then
˚F分配到 B-分配器 ，然后
to really make a good allocator like an
要真正做一个好的分配像
a allocator you need to use sugar is
你需要使用糖是分配器
lists which we'll look at in a second
列出了我们来看看在 第二
okay so the explicit list now the the
好了，所以明确的名单现在的
allocation time is linear in the number
分配时间是在数线性
of free blocks instead of the total size
的空闲块代替 的总大小
of the instead of the total size of the
的代替的总大小
heap so it's this is much faster than
堆所以它的这个 比快得多
that when you have a lot of allocated
当你有很多的分配
blocks it's a little more complicated
块这是一个有点复杂
because of all the splicing business and
因为 所有的拼接业务和
and you do need some extra space in your
而你需要做一些额外的空间，你的
for these pointers which increases the
对于这些指针，这增加了
minimum block size and creates
最小的块大小，并创建
additional overhead now the link list
现在 的额外 开销的链接 列表
the explicit list allocators aren't
明确的名单分配器不
really sufficient enough to be used for
真的足够足够 用于
sort of general purpose real-life
排序通用 现实生活 的
allocator but they are useful in as part
分配器，但他们是在为部分有用
of a segregated list allocator so you
一个隔离列表 分配的，所以你
can have you can have multiple free
可以有你可以有 多个免费
lists each of which is an explicit list
列出每一个都是一个明确的列表
and it's fine for that for that
和它的罚款 ，对于该
application alright so let's look at our
应用好了让我们看看我们
third method which is to create call a
第三种 方法 是创建 一个呼叫
segregated free list which is to have
隔离自由列表，它是有
multiple free lists with different size
不同尺寸的多个自由列表
classes so the the idea is that each
班所以这个想法是，每个
each class of sizes block sizes has its
每个类大小的块大小的具有其
own free list and that that class can be
自己的自由列表和那类可以
singleton you know maybe a one
单身，你也许知道 一个
particular size or it can be a range of
特定大小或它可以是一个范围
sizes so you might you might have a
大小，所以 你 可能你可能 有一个
number of different you know if your if
你知道，如果 你如果 不同数量
your if your workload consists of a lot
你的 ，如果你的工作负载包括大量的
of these small blocks and you know that
这些小块的，你知道，
there's going to be a lot of requests
还有的将是大量 的 请求
for blocks of 1 through 4 you can have
对于一个1-4块，你可以 有
different free lists for those small for
对于那些小的不同的空闲列表
those small block sizes and then after
那些小的块大小和在此之后
that you can go and just do ranges of
你可以去 ，只是做的范围
power of 2 so that's a that's a common
2的幂所以这是一个这是一个常见的
technique so here we have a size class
技术，因此在这里我们有一个尺寸级别
that covers blocks from size 5 to 8 and
覆盖从大小为5块〜8和
then another size class that covers
然后另一个尺寸类覆盖
everything else
一切
so the idea with the seg list allocators
所以与赛格 名单 分配器的想法
that given a given an array of these
该给定 的 这些 给定的阵列
free lists one each one for for some
免费名单一个个针对一些
size class if we want to allocate a
如果我们想分配尺寸类
block of size n then we we go to the
大小为n的块，然后我们我们去
appropriate free list right there's only
合适的自由列表右边有只
there's always going to be one free list
人们总是将是一个免费列表
for any any end and then we search that
对于任何任意结束，然后我们说搜索
list just like we did before
列表就像我们以前那样
for some size if a block size M greater
对于某些尺寸 如果块尺寸M大
than n and then if we find it then we
大于n，然后如果我们发现那我们
place we place the new block we place
地方，我们将新的块我们把
the block in that in the block that we
在块中，该块，我们
found we split it and we take this the
发现我们把它分解，我们采取这种
split block and we put it into the
分块，我们把它放到
appropriate size class so that the block
适当的尺寸类，使得块
that we split off may or may not may or
我们分出可用可不用的可能或
may not belong to the current size class
可能不属于目前的规模类
anymore and so we may have to move it
了，所以我们可能要 移动它
and insert it into a whatever the
并且将其插入任何 的
appropriate size class is if there's no
适当大小的类是如果没有
block if we can't find a block then we
块，如果我们不能找到一个块，然后我们
have to try the next larger size class
要尝试下一个较大的尺寸级别
okay so it's possible for a given size
好了，所以它 可能对于给定 尺寸
class they're just there might not be a
类，他们只是有可能不是 一个
block that fits so I mean one so we just
块， 适合 所以我的意思是一个，所以我们只是
have to we go to the next size we try
要 我们去，我们尝试下大小
the next larger class and chances are
下一个更大的类和机会
we'll find a block that fits there and
我们会找到适合有一个块
if we and you keep doing that until you
如果你一直这样做，直到你
eventually if you can't find it you're
最终如果你不能找到你
eventually looking in the size class
最终看在尺寸级别
that that that covers all the rest the
这是覆盖所有的休息
last size class and if then you can't
最后径级，如果再你不能
find it then that the allocator has to
找到它，然后，该分配器具有
allocate more memory with by colleen s
与由科琳小号分配更多的内存
break
打破
okay to free a block you coalesce like
还好释放你凝聚像块
before and then you place it on the
之前， 然后你将它放在
appropriate list so that's that's
相应的列表所以这是这
straightforward and again you have this
简单 ，再次你 有这样的
option to try to maintain the listed
选项来尝试维持上市
address ordered or just do the simple
地址订购或只是做简单的
thing and put it at the beginning of the
事情 并把它在 的 开始
list okay so say egg list alligators are
列出好了，所以说 鸡蛋 列表 鳄鱼是
that by far the best type of alligator
这是迄今为止鳄鱼最好的类型
because they they offer you improvements
因为他们为您提供改进
in both performance throughput and
在性能和吞吐量
memory utilization so they're faster
内存利用率所以他们更快
they have higher throughputs because the
他们有更高的吞吐量，因为
the individual size classes are are
个体大小类是
smaller then than just like the one
然后比就像一个小
giant free list but also you're
巨人空闲列表， 而且你
searching you know that the list that
搜索你知道 列表
you're searching is going to be close to
您正在搜索将是接近
the size that you're looking for so the
您正在寻找这样的大小
chances of finding something quickly in
快速找到东西的机会
that in that particular size class are
在那个 特定的大小类 是
higher than they are if you're just
高于他们，如果你只是
searching on you know a single free list
搜索你想知道一个免费列表
that holds all different size classes
保存所有不同规模类
okay so search is faster so that
好了，搜索速度更快，使
increases increases throughput but the
上升增加吞吐量，但
big thing about egg list alligators is
关于鸡蛋 列表鳄鱼大的事情是
that like we talked about before they
像我们之前，他们谈到了
approximate best fit without sacrificing
接近最适合在不牺牲
performance right before if we wanted to
演出前的权利，如果我们想
do best fit on a single a free list we
做最适合于单一空闲列表我们
had to search the whole free list and
不得不搜索整个空闲列表和
then choose the block that's it the best
然后选择这是它最好的块
in this case we get we get best fit for
在这种情况下，我们也得到了我们获得最适合
free by by virtue of having these size
释放由通过具有这些尺寸的
classes and so this is you know this is
类等，这是你知道这 是
this is how you can improve your your
这是你如何能提高你的
memory utilization yes
内存利用率是
to me this alligator and more bite or
对我来说这鳄鱼，更咬伤或
next oh yeah yeah good question so the
下哦耶，耶，很好的问题，因此
question is is is break constant time it
问题 是是是打破固定的 时间它
is but it's very expensive so it's a
是，但它是非常昂贵 ，因此这是一个
Cisco so it has to pass from user space
思科所以它必须从用户空间传递
into the kernel that involves changing
到涉及更改内核
contacts changing stacks so it's this
联系人改变栈所以它的 这个
call generally you can you can count on
叫一般来说，你可以，你可以指望
assist call being like several hundred
协助呼叫是像几百
microseconds okay it's a non-trivial
微秒还好这是一个不平凡的
overhead and so in that case you
开销，所以在这种情况下，你
wouldn't want you you want to amortize
我不想让你要 分摊
the cost of the of the break by
的突破的费用由
allocating a somewhat larger chunk but
分配稍大块，但
you have to be careful if you allocate
你必须要小心，如果你分配
too large of a chunk then your memory
过大的块，然后对你的记忆
utilization goes down so it's a
利用率下降所以这是一个
trade-off it's another one of these
权衡它的这些一个又一个
space-time trade-offs question so where
时空权衡问题，以便在那里
do you store this array of free list so
你存储在此阵列 的空闲列表 等等
you store it in the beginning of the
你将它存储在的开始
heat yeah in fact for your Mallik lab we
热啊，其实你Mallik实验中我们
require you to do that we don't know and
要求你要做到这一点，我们不 知道和
the reason is we can't bat that array of
原因是我们不能蝙蝠进行阵列
sex in some small part depending on how
这取决于如何做爱在一些小部分
large that array is it affects your
大数组是它会影响您的
memory utilization and so it should be
内存利用率，所以它应该 是
at the beginning of the heat
在热的 开始
okay there's a allocators have been
还好有一个分配器已
around forever and the the the classic
撒手人寰和的经典
references Canute's the 1973 text and
引用克努特的1973年 文本 和
there's also this great paper which you
这里还有这个伟大的纸， 你
can get from the book's website from
可以从 本书的网站 得到
1995 that does a survey of you know
1995年，做你的调查知道
little dozens and dozens of techniques
小数十座技术
like we're just scratching the surface
就像我们只是表面
here so if you're really interested in
所以在这里，如果你真正感兴趣
this stuff that that papers a
这个东西，那试卷
fascinating read and it may give you
迷人的读取和它可能给你
some ideas for your prelab okay now so
现在没事了一些想法，供 大家实验预习 所以
far we're assuming that the application
目前为止我们还假设应用程序
is responsible for both allocating
同时负责 分配
storage and freeing storage but there's
存储和释放存储，但有
there a form of memory managers called
有内存管理的一种形式叫
implicit memory managers that do the
内隐记忆经理们做的
freeing for you so so applications
释放你那么那么的应用
allocate space but they never have to
分配空间，但他们从来没有
worry about freeing space the system
担心释放空间系统
does that automatically and so the the
这是否自动所以在
idea is to identify so-called garbage so
思想是 确定所谓的垃圾等等
areas of memory that can never be
内存方面是绝不可能
referenced anymore and then free up
再引用，然后释放
those blocks
这些块
so what's garbage well here's an example
所以什么是垃圾以及这里是一个 例子
we have a function foo that now likes
我们有一个函数foo，现在喜欢
128 bytes it stores the address in this
128个字节它 在此 存储的地址
pointer P and then at some point when it
指针P，然后在某个时刻 ，当它
returns from foo this pointer is lost
从FOO返回该指针丢失
forever right because P is a local
永远正确的，因为P是一个地方
variable on the stack so once once this
在 堆栈 上 可变 所以一旦这一次
function returns that the block of
函数返回的块
memory pointed to by P is garbage can
存储器由p指向的是垃圾罐
never be referenced again because
永远不会再因为引用
there's no way there's no way for the
有没有办法， 没有 办法的
program to get get access to that and so
程序获得到达那个等访问
what an allocator will recognize at some
什么样的 分配会认识一些
point that this block of of memory is
指出这一点的存储器的这个块是
garbage and that it will free those
垃圾，它会释放那些
blocks by calling free it's the same
通过调用free这是相同的块
kind of exactly the same free call as
实物一模一样的 免费通话为
we've discussed but now it's called by
我们已经讨论过，但现在它是由被称为
the garbage collector not
垃圾收集器不
the application okay so you see this in
应用好让你在看到这个
all different kinds of dynamic languages
各种不同类型的动态语言
and there's there's there's also
而且也有有也
variants available for C but because of
对于C，但由于可用的变种
C's pointer properties that the garbage
C'S 指针性的垃圾
collectors for C are conservative in the
对于C收藏家都在保守
sense that there's some blocks won't be
某种意义上说 有一些块不会
freed there's some garbage blocks that
释放有一些垃圾块是
that won't be free because the allocator
这不会是免费的，因为分配器
can't determine that that they are
不能确定它们 是
indeed garbage so it has to be careful
的确垃圾所以它必须要小心
when it whenever there's a doubt it it
当它只要有疑问，这是
leaves it doesn't reclaim the the
叶不回收的
allocated block so it gets to this
分配的块所以它得到这个
question of like how does the memory
像问题如何 做内存
manager know when memory can be free and
经理知道什么时候存储可以是自由的
you know if we knew if somehow we knew
你知道，如果我们知道，如果我们不知何故知道
we could predict all of the future
我们可以预测所有的未来
requests and then if we knew that there
请求，然后如果我们知道 有
were no future requests access that
是没有前途的请求 访问
block and we could free it okay but we
块，我们可以释放它 不错，但我们
can't predict that okay so we have to
无法预测好了，所以我们必须
but if there's no pointers if no
但如果没有指针，如果没有
pointers exist to a particular block
指针存在于特定块
then we know that it can't be accessed
那么我们知道， 它不能 被访问
okay and so that we can predict right if
可以的，这样我们就 可以正确的预测，如果
there's some way we can sort of a scan
有一些方法，我们 可以排序扫描
the program identify or scan the memory
节目识别或扫描存储器
identify all the pointers in that memory
识别内存的所有指针
and and see which which blocks have
并且部分，查看哪些块有
pointed to and it's there if they're not
指出了它的存在，如果他们不
pointed to by any pointer then then
指向任何指针然后 然后
they're garbage by definition okay so to
他们的定义是垃圾 好了，所以到
do this though it's difficult so first
做到这一点，虽然这是 很难使第一
of all the memory manager has to be able
所有的内存管理器必须能够
to distinguish pointers from non
区分非指针
pointers which we can't do and see right
指针这是我们不能做的，见右图
they're just these
他们只是这些
they're just these integral values right
他们只是这些积分值权
we don't know it could be it if we see
我们不知道它可能 是 ，如果我们看到
this large integral value this large
这个大的积分值这个大
long eight byte value it could be it
长一个八字节的值，它可能是它
could be pointing to a data structure it
可以指向一个数据结构， 它
could just be a large integer right we
可能仅仅是一个大的整数正确的，我们
don't know and then we also all pointers
不知道，然后我们还所有指针
have to point to the start of a block
必须指向一个块的开始
which is not true and see either
这是不正确的，要么看
okay so if we have a pointer and we
好吧，如果我们有 一个指针，我们
identify that at the pointer then we
确定在指针 那么我们
know that it points it points to some
知道它指向它指出了一些
block if it points inside of a block how
如果阻止它指向一个块怎样的内部
do we how do we find the beginning of
我们怎么办，我们发现的开端
that block you know how do we know how
你知道块我们怎么知道如何
big that block is so it has to point to
大该块是 如此有指向
the beginning of the block or the header
块或首部的 开头
tells us the size and the and and and
告诉我们的规模和和和和
there can't be a way to hide pointers
不能有隐瞒指针方式
the point that the property of being a
该点的是一个属性
pointer has to be some kind of static
指针必须是某种静态
saying that doesn't that can't change so
说没有不能改变，因此
that's sort of the challenges if you're
这是排序 的挑战 ，如果你
thinking about how in the world can you
思考如何在世界上你
implement a garbage collector so those
实现垃圾收集所以那些
are some of the challenges that that
是 一些 的 挑战
they present and because of that it's
他们目前正因为它的
been a history of research and garbage
成为 研究和垃圾 史
collectors it is old its ancient and
收藏家它是旧的古老和
ongoing it's still it's still ongoing
目前它仍然是它仍在进行中
today particularly in the context of
今天特别是在上下文
parallel programs and garbage collecting
并行程序和垃圾收集
programs that are running multiple
运行多个程序
threads so there's a whole bunch of
线程，以便有一大堆
these things that people have looked at
这些东西，人们已经看
going all the way back to 1960
将所有的方式 回到1960年
today we'll look at we'll look at the
今天我们来看看，我们将看看
simplest what one of the simpler
较简单的最简单的一个东西
variants called mark-and-sweep and we
变种称为标记和清除，我们
won't we won't discuss the rest but if
不会，我们不会讨论休息，但如果
you're interested in them there's a
你有兴趣他们有一个
pretty good book that describes that
相当不错的书 ， 描述
describes these things all right so how
描述这些东西没事所以如何
do we build an allocator so we start by
我们建立一个 分配 ，所以我们通过启动
viewing memory as a directed graph where
观看存储器作为向图，其中
each each node in the graph corresponds
图中的每一个相对应的每个节点
to a block okay a block a heap block and
到一个块行的块的堆块和
eaten out an allocated heap block and
食用出分配的堆块 和
each edge is a pointer that's contained
每个边缘是真实包含一个指针
somewhere within that block pointer to
内的块指针到某处
another block and then there's a and
另一个块，然后有一个和
then there's special nodes called root
再有就是 所谓的根 特殊节点
nodes that contain pointers into the
包含指针到节点
heap but they're not part of the heap so
堆，但他们不是堆的一部分，所以
for example pointers that are stored on
为存储 在 例如指针
the stack pointers that are stored in
存储 在 所述堆栈指针
registers they point to memory locations
寄存器它们指向的存储器位置
in the heap
在堆
but nothing nothing and but there
但没有什么和但是有
outside of the heat so and we call those
热量 ，使 之外 ，我们呼吁那些
root notes so nothing points to them or
根音所以没有点对他们或
at least if something does point to them
至少，如果事情不指向它们
we don't care about what it is okay
我们不关心 什么 是好的
we're only we're only concerned about
我们只是我们只关心
characterizing nodes that correspond to
对应于表征节点
memory in the heap so I we say that a
内存堆，所以我我们说
node or a block is reachable if there's
节点或 块是可到达的，如果有
some path from a root node from a root
从根节点 从根一些路径
node to that block so and we've denoted
节点到该块左右，我们已经记
those by green so all of these green
那些绿色的 ，因此所有 这些绿色的
blocks in the heap are reachable because
在堆块是可到达的，因为
you can start at a root node and just
你可以在根节点处开始，只是
follow some some sequence of pointers to
跟随指针的一些部分序列
get to that node okay
到达该节点 好吗
notes that aren't reachable are called
注释所有不可 被称为
our garbage because there's no there's
我们的垃圾 ，因为没有有
no way to get to them from the root
没有办法让他们从根
nodes okay so there's no node inside the
节点好了，里面有无节点
heat that points to them and there's no
热指向他们，而且也没有
node there's no root node that points to
节点有指向没有根节点
them so basically there's just no path
他们所以基本上只是 没有路径
from a root node that'll get you to one
从根节点是会得到你 一个
of these non reachable or garbage nodes
这些非可到达 或垃圾节点
and since they're non reachable the
而因为他们是不可到达的
application will never be able to
应用程序将永远无法
reference them in the future so we can
引用他们的未来，所以我们 可以
predict with certainty that that those
肯定地说， 这些预测
are garbage and they can be freed okay
都是垃圾，他们可以 没事 被释放
so basically after we free these then
所以基本上我们后释放这些 再
they're removed from the graph
他们从图中移除
so now we can we can build a simple
所以现在我们可以我们可以建立一个简单的
garbage collector on top of the existing
在现有的顶部垃圾收集器
malloc and free package right so you
malloc和free包装正​​确，因此您
implement now I can free just like
现在实行我可以自由就像
before and then you if the program calls
之前， 然后你如果程序调用
malloc just like before and you just you
malloc的只是像以前一样，你 只是你
do malloc exactly the same way until you
做的malloc完全相同的方式，直到你
run out of space by whatever definition
不论如何定义 运行的 空间
you want to use of running out of space
要使用空间耗尽的
maybe you have some kind of maximum each
也许你有某种形式的最大 每一
size you're willing to use or at some
大小你愿意在一些使用或
point the OS will just stop giving you
点OS将只是停止给你
virtual memory when you run out of space
当你运行 的空间虚拟内存
you you add an extra mark bit into the
你，你添加一个额外的标志位进入
header of each block so this could be
每个块的首标所以这可能 是
you know we have like three or four
你知道我们有像三个或四个
spare bits that we can use in the header
我们可以在标题中使用备用位
so we can denote one of those that's the
所以我们可以表示 其中的一个是这样的
mark bit and then we are garbage
标志位，然后我们都是垃圾
collection our garbage collection phase
我们收集的垃圾收集阶段
when we run out of space consists of two
当我们运行的空间由两
two different sub phases one is the mark
两个不同的子阶段之一是该标记
phase which starts at all the roots and
阶段开始于所有的根和
then and it just traverses this from the
然后，它只是遍历这个从
roots it traverses the set of of nodes
根遍历集合 的节点
that are reachable from the root and it
是从 根和 它 到达
sets the mark that in each each one of
设定标记的是在每个各一个
those nodes ok and then once after you
这些节点确定，然后后 你 一次
finish marking all of the all of the
完成标志着所有的所有的
reachable blocks then you sweep through
可到达的块，然后你通过扫
the entire heap starting at the very
整个堆起始于 非常
beginning of the heap and you look for
堆的 开始 ，你看
you look for all allocated blocks that
你看所有分配的块是
aren't marked okay because they're not
因为他们不是 没有标记 好吗
marked they're not reachable in their
标志着他们在没有到达他们的
garbage
垃圾
sofirst so you do this so you sort of do
sofirst所以你这样做，所以你之类 的做
- you do a search from the from the
-你从从做搜索
roots and then you do a sweep of the
根， 那么你做的扫描
entire heat
整个热
so let's say before the for mark we have
所以我们说， 以前 的标志，我们有
a before the marks phase we have a heap
一个标记阶段之前，我们有一个 堆
that looks like this we have a single
看起来像这一点，我们有一个单一的
root that points to this block and what
根指向此块什么
we're going to do here we're always
我们要在这里做 我们总是
going to point to the payload right of
要指出的有效载荷权
the of the block just a convention that
该块只是一个约定
we use so we're pointing to the
我们使用所以我们指向
beginning of the block because we know
块的 开始 ，因为我们知道
that it's we know that the the header is
这是我们知道的是，标题是
one one word behind it and so let's say
一个一个字背后，并让我们说
and in this case the the edges denote
并且在这种情况下，边缘表示
pointers that are contained in the block
中包含的块的指针
so they're not the previous and next
所以他们不是 一个和 下一个
pointers that we were maintaining these
三分球是我们 维护这些
are just pointers that the application
仅会指向应用程序
has put into those blocks so we have so
已投产 的区块，所以我们 有这么
here we have the root pointing to this
在这里，我们有根指向这个
central block and then there's and and
中央 块，然后有 和和
there's a pointer that points to this
还有一个指向该指针
block and there's another pointer that
阻止和有另一个指针
points to this block and and there's a
指向该块，并有一个
pointer in this block that points to
指针在该块中指向
this block so after we do the mark and
该块所以我们做了标记后
we search this we search these blocks
我们搜索这个我们寻找这些块
and all of the reachable blocks have the
和所有可达块的有
mark bit set which is denoted by tink
标志位组是由天衣表示
and so then you see a net and then the
所以，你看到一个网， 然后
the blocks that aren't aren't marked
未未标记块
then we can free and return to the free
那么我们可以免费并返回到自由
list
名单
okay so let's look at the assumptions
好了，让我们来看看假设
for a simple implementation just to make
一个简单的实现 只是为了让
make sure this is clear so the
确保这是明显的，因此
application calls new to get a pointer
应用程序调用新获取一个指针
to a block with with all those values
到块与所有这些值
cleared it calls read D I to read
清除它调用读 DI阅读
location I of Block B and it uses write
B座的位置，我和它使用 的写
div to write a value V into location I
DIV写值 V 到我的位置
of Block B then each block will have a
嵌段B的那么每个块将有 一个
header word which will address as B of
报头字将解决作为乙
minus 1 and then the garbage collector
减1，然后将垃圾收集器
has it has functions that it uses to
拥有它，使用它来功能
identify whether a pointer whether its
识别是否指针是否其
input parameter is indeed a pointer ok
输入参数确实是一个指针确定
so there's some way to distinguish a
所以有一些方法来区分
pointer from an on pointer and it can
从指针上的指针 ，它可以
get the length of some block not
得到一些块的长度不
including the header and it can get a
包括头，它可以得到一个
set of all of the routes so given those
将所有所以给出的路线的
given those assumptions we our
鉴于这些假设我们我们
pseudocode for the mark step it takes so
伪代码标记为一步需要这么
this initially is a is a pointer a route
这最初是一个是一个指针的 路线
pointer okay and then we check as our
指针好 ，然后我们检查作为我们的
terminating condition we check to see if
中止条件，我们检查，看看 是否
that that input is indeed a pointer and
这是输入确实是一个指针，
if so we return okay and then then we do
如果是这样，我们返回没关系，然后那么我们呢
a depth-first traversal of the of the
的的一个深度优先遍历
graph so if and this so we're doing a
图所以如果这个，所以我们正在做一个
depth-first traversal of the graph and
该图的深度优先遍历和
this is pointer is sort of our
这是指针是那种我们
terminating condition for that that
终止条件为的是
depth-first traversal then we check the
深度优先遍历然后我们检查
mark bit and if it's set then that's
标志位，如果它被设置 那么这
another terminating condition there's no
另一个终止条件没有
there's no reason to search once we find
没有理由进行搜索，一旦发现
a marked marked node we know that all of
一个明显的标记点，我们知道，所有的
everything reachable from that node is
一切从到达该节点
is marked so we we can terminate our
被标记，所以我们 就可以终止我们
return and just stop the search if it's
返回，只是停止搜索，如果它是
not set then we set the mark bit and
没有设置那么我们设置 标志位和
then we look at each word in the block
接下来我们来看看每个字块中
and we recursively call mark on each one
我们递归调用每个1马克
of those words now each one of those
的那些 字现在 那些 中的每一个
words may or may not be a pointer right
字可以 是 或可以 不是一个正确的指针
so if it's not a pointer then mark will
所以，如果它不是一个指针，然后标记将
just return instantly immediately if it
刚刚返回瞬间立即如果
is a pointer then it will continue the
是一个指针，那么它将继续
recursive depth first search okay so
递归深度优先搜索好了，
does that make sense it's just a
这是否感觉它只是 一个
familiar the familiar depth-first graph
熟悉熟悉的深度优先图表
traversal of it that we all know about
它穿越我们都知道
okay and then the sweep sweep take a
没关系， 然后扫描扫取
pointer to the beginning of the heat
指针热的开始
this first take the pointer to the first
这第一个 带指针到第一
block in the heat and then some pointer
块在热，然后一些指针
to the end of the heat and then in a
到热的端部，然后在
while loop then it scans the heap each
while循环然后它扫描每个堆
block if the mark bit is set it clears
如果阻断标志位被设置它清除
it
它
if it if it's allocated it frees it
如果它，如果它的分配它释放它
right
对
and then it updates and then it gets the
然后它更新，然后得到
address of the the next block and then
的 下一个块 ， 然后 的地址
just continues until the end okay so how
只是一直持续到年底好了，所以如何
do we do such a thing in C right because
我们用 C正确的，因为做这样的事情
all of these assumptions I've made don't
所有这些假设我做的不
hold and C you can't tell a pointer from
持有和C，你不能告诉从一个指针
an on pointer pointers can point
一个上指示器指针可以指向
anywhere so what you could do so the big
任何地方，所以你可以做的这么大
issue is that if we get some value we it
问题是，如果我们得到了一些价值，我们就
even if it is a pointer it could point
即使它是一个指针它可以指向
right into the middle of the block so
权成块的中间 如此
given that so first of all we don't know
鉴于所以首先 我们不知道
if that value really is a pointer it
如果该值 确实是一个指针，它
could just be a big integer but it also
可能仅仅是一个大的整数，但它也
could be a pointer that's pointing into
可能是已指向指针
some data structure so if it is a
一些数据结构，所以如果它是一个
pointer how do we how do we find the
指针，我们怎么办，我们怎么找
beginning of the block so what we could
块的开始，使我们能
do is just assume that every value is a
要做的仅仅是假设每个值是
pointer and then we maintain a balance
指针，然后我们保持平衡
tree to keep track of all the allocated
树来跟踪 所有分配
blocks and so whenever we encounter a
块，所以每当我们遇到
particular value we would search that
特别是价值，我们将搜索该
binary tree to see if it assuming it is
二叉树，看它是否假设它是
a pointer is it falls within the the
一个指针是它属于内的
beginning and end of some allocated
开始，分配的一些终端
block okay if if that condition is true
阻止没关系，如果如果条件为真
then we assume that it's pointing that
那么我们假设 它指向的是
that's a pointer to an allocated block
这是一个指向 分配的 块
and we assume that that block is
我们假设该块是
reachable now the reason it's
到达现在它的原因
conservative is because it really may
保守是因为它确实可能
not be a pointer it might be this
没有它可能是这个指针
integer and we'll we'll assume it's a
整数，我们将我们假设这是一个
pointer and assume that the block that
指针并假定块
it purportedly points to is allocated
据称它指向被分配
but it may in fact be not be a pointer
但它实际上可能不会是一个指针
and the block that it points to is
和它指向该块是
garbage right so what with this with
垃圾权等什么与此同
this scheme we would leave some some non
这个方案我们会留下一些一些非
non reachable blocks we will indicate
非可达块，我们将指示
that some non reachable blocks are are
一些非可达块是
really reachable
真正到达
okay so so once now that we've got this
好了，所以一旦现在，我们已经有了这个
great tool to dynamically allocate
伟大的工具来动态分配
memory we can use it in our programs and
内存我们可以在 程序中 使用它 ，
shoot ourselves in the foot in all
拍摄自己在所有的脚
different kinds of ways okay so I'm
各种不同的 方式好了，所以我
going to I'm going to try to help help
要我要 尽力帮助帮助
you out here by identifying some of the
你在这里通过识别某些
perils and pitfalls that that we can run
危险和陷阱是，我们可以运行
into it with with memory related
把 它与内存相关
operations or operations on memory and
内存操作或操作 和
opera errors errors involving memory are
涉及内存歌剧错误错误
the worst the worst kinds of bugs to try
最坏最坏的类型的bug 尝试
to find out and the reason is that
找出其原因是，
they're distant in both space and time
他们在遥远的空间和 时间
so let's say you write to the wrong
让我们说你写了错误的
memory location and corrupt some data
内存位置和腐败的一些数据
structures the right doesn't elicit any
结构的权利并不引起任何
error you only find out about that illy
错误只了解这 意利
that erroneous right when you try to
当您尝试错误权
reference that data structure or that
参考该数据结构或
particular part of the data structure
的数据结构 的特定部分
which may be in a part of the code
其可以是在代码的一部分
that's way far away from the right that
这是方式远离正确 的，
caused the problem both in space you
造成这个问题无论是在你的空间
know in distance you know lines of code
知道在远方的你知道的代码行
it could be a completely different
它可能是一个完全不同的
function and a completely different
功能和 一个完全不同的
module but also in time it may not you
模块还要及时也可能没有你
know you may do the right and then eons
不知道你会做正确的， 然后永世
later other some read and it fails right
后来其他一些阅读和失败的权利
so this is a fundamental thing that
所以这是 一个基本的东西 ，
makes memory related bugs just so nasty
使得内存相关的错误只是这么讨厌
and another big thing another thing that
另有 一件大事另一件事
makes them hard to deal with is people's
使他们很难 处理是人们
misunderstanding and misuse of pointers
误解和指针的滥用
right so usually an erroneous right is
右所以通常的错误权是
some is some either a misunderstanding
一些是一些或者是误解
of pointers or an improperly initialized
的指针或不正确初始化
pointer so it all boils down to these
指针，这一切都归结到这些
pointers okay and so I'm going to show
指针可以的，所以我要 告诉
you how to understand pointers okay for
你如何理解指针为好
the first time in your lives
第一次在你的生活
I don't know about you but when I
我不知道你 ，但 我
learned C I learned about pointers I
据悉 CI了解我的指针
just knew about what a few different
只知道什么几个不同
types of pointers were by and I did it
类型的指针被我做到了
by pattern matching so I knew that int
通过模式匹配，所以我知道这个 int
star P was a pointer to an int I knew
星p在指向 我知道 一个int
that int star star P was was an array
这个int星星p在是一个阵列
I knew that int star key Open bracket
我知道，INT星号键打开支架
close bracket was also an array just a
闭括号也是阵列只是 一个
different way to express that a race I
不同的方式来表达 那一场比赛我
had a small handful of pointers types
有指针类型一小撮
that I could deal with but I had no
我能对付，但我没有
underlying understanding of what that
根本的是什么的认识
meant or anything was just pure pattern
意味着什么 的只是纯粹的模式
matching and I'll bet you that's the way
匹配和 我敢打赌，你就是这样
you do it too
你这样做太
all right but that's all going to change
好的 ，但是这一切都将改变
today
今天
all right so in order to really
没事如此，才能真正
understand pointers you need to
了解指针你需要
understand the precedence of various
了解各种优先
operators in C because the pointer types
在C运算因为指针类型
are declared using these operators and
使用这些运营商都宣布和
so my copy of K and R it has a dog-eared
所以我的K和R其副本有一个折角
at page 53 this table comes from page 53
在53页的这张表 来自53页
of knr and you should have a paper clip
KNR的，你应该有一个 文件夹
or have that folded over for reference
或具有折叠以供参考
now the thing to notice is that function
现在要注意的一点是，函数
and array and then and these struct
和数组，然后和这些结构
these various struct operators have the
这些不同的结构运营商具备
highest priority highest precedence and
最高 优先级最高优先级 和
that and then that's followed by unary
这一点，那么，再接一元
operators so the star this is the
所以运营商的明星，这是
dereference operator and then the the
引用操作，然后将
address of operator these there they
这些运营商中有他们的地址
fall right below the highest the highest
落在下方的最高最高
precedence operators and then the binary
优先级运营商，然后二进制
versions of operators in order to use in
为了 在 使用运营商的版本
arithmetic operations are below those
算术运算是低于
okay so just remember that function and
好了，只记得函数
array is higher than star okay
数组比明星更高好吗
that to do the dereference now the great
是做现在取消引用伟大
thing about pointers although they
关于指针虽然他们的事
always seem really complicated is that
似乎总是很复杂 的是，
there's there's an algorithm for it for
有有一个算法，它
there's an algorithm for constructing an
还有一种构造的算法
English sentence that explains exactly
英语句子 正好 说明
what what that pointer what that
什么什么是指针什么
definition of the pointer means okay and
指针 的定义是指行和
if you're interested it's in the KN are
如果你有兴趣它在 KN是
in Section 5.1 - but I'll I'll explain
5.1节-但我会我会解释
it to you now now I don't know I don't
它现在现在我不知道，我不
know how much in this class you're going
知道 你 有多少在 这个类 中 去
to remember okay but I guarantee you
记得不错，但我向你保证
you're going to remember this as the day
你要记住这为天
you finally understood pointers okay so
你终于明白了指针好了，
all right so here's how it works you
好吧 所以这里的它是如何运作的 ，你
always start it the this is a definition
始终启动它，这是一个定义
of a pointer some kind you always start
指针 某种你总是 启动
with the variable name
变量名称
and then you use your precedence then
然后你用你的优先级，然后
you look for operators on either side of
你看运营商的两边
that varial variable name and you choose
你选择维里的变量名
the one that has the highest precedence
具有最高 优先级的一个
okay so we start with the variable so we
好了，所以我们先从变量，所以我们
say t is a then we look to the left and
说T 是接下来我们来看看 左，
the right there's nothing to the right
没有什么是 对的权利
but there's a there's a pointer symbol
但有一个有一个指针符号
to the left so we say t is a pointer and
向左所以我们 说 t 是一个指针，
there's nothing more and then we always
没有什么更多的，然后我们始终
end up with the the type of thing that
结束了 的东西的类型
it points that so P is a pointer to int
它指出，如此P是一个指针为int
like Sookie is P as a pointer to some to
像的Sookie是P作为指针一些到
some integer in memory okay so we all
在内存的整数好了 ，所以大家都
know that one that's pretty easy okay
知道，一说是很 容易 没关系
what about the next one you've probably
你可能已经 对下 一个是什么
seen something like this
看到这样的事情
some programs declare our D using this
某些程序中声明使用此我们ð
notation and so this you can have an
符号所以这个你可以有一个
optional size or not so so we always
可选的大小或并非 如此，所以我们总是
start out we say T is a well now in this
开始时我们说T 是现在好了在这个
case there's operators to the left and
万一有公司运营的左侧和
the right
正确的
remember the array operator has higher
记得数组运算符具有较高
precedence than that the the
优先级高于该
dereferencing operator the pointer
对其操作的指针
operators so we say so T is an array 13
运营商所以我们说所以T是阵列 13
array of size 13 of so there's nothing
尺寸13的阵列所以没有什么
more so we go to the left of pointers so
更使我们去指针的左边，这样
T is an array 13 of pointers to ends
T是一个指针数组13到端部
so t is an array of 13 pointers each of
所以t是 每13个指针 的数组
which points to an end right in this
它指向该结束的权利
case P is just that the name of the
情况P 就是这样 的名字
array so bytes by default P P is a is
阵列所以默认 字节 P P是是
equivalent is the address of the array
当量是 数组 的地址
when you reference an array name you're
当你引用 你是 一个数组名
you're you're addressing your active
你是 你在解决您 主动
dressing the address of the first
穿衣第一的地址
element okay how about the next one here
元素好吗怎么样在这里下单
we're being if we put parentheses around
我们是如果我们把周围的括号
things then we can be explicit okay and
接下来的事情，我们可以明确的很好，而且
this is a good practice so here we're
这 是一个很好的做法，让我们在这里是
saying T and we have to look at this one
说T和我们来看看 这个
first because of the parenthesis so T is
第一因为 括号 所以T是
an array thirteen of pointers to ends so
指针数组13以 端部，从而
that's the same thing and here we're
这是同样的事情 ，在这里我们是
just being more explicit
只是被更明确
now what about star star T so P is a
现在关注的明星一T因此P是什么
pointer to a pointer to an int okay so
指针的指针为int好了，
this is a different type of array
这是一个不同类型的数组
so P is a pointer to a pointer to an end
所以P是一个指针 的指针 结束
okay and and typically so this is
很好，而且和一般，所以这是
another way to do a raise so the same
另一种方式做到加薪 所以同样
way the char star points to a string
这样的炭星点为一个字符串
this this can point it points to it
这本可以指向它指向它
points to up a pointer but then you can
指向了一个指针，但那么你就可以
index on that each one of those ven
上， 这些中的每一个索引VEN
points corresponds to a pointer whoops
点对应于指针哎呦
okay here's another one now P because
还好这里的另一个现在 一个 P，因为
and because of the parentheses we have
因为括号的 ，我们有
to go left so P is a pointer to an array
向左走所以P是一个指针 数组
13 of Imps okay so P isn't a pointer to
印象数的13行，从而P 不是 指针
an array of 13 inch
的 13英寸 的阵列
all right now what about this one
现在好了这个怎么样
f is a function or is it a function or a
f是函数或者是一个功能或
pointer F is a function right because of
指针F是因为正确的函数
the precedence so f is a F is a function
的优先，因此f 是 F是函数
returning pointer to int okay so if we
返回指针为int好了，所以如果我们
go if we go P equal F then that returns
去，如果我们去P等于˚F那么回报
that initialized P to point to some int
该初始化p来指向一些INT
all right and I'm going to do this one
没事，我要 做到这一点一个
let's jump down in the interest of time
让我们跳下来的时间关系
totally ridiculous case just so you can
完全荒谬的情况下， 只是让你可以
see that this algorithm works
看到这个算法的工作
all right so X is an array of pointers
所有 权利，使X是一个指针数组
to functions returning pointers to an
在返回 指针到一个 功能
array five events and if you ever use
阵列五个 事件，如果你曾经使用
anything like that in your code shame on
类似 的事情在你的 代码 的耻辱
you all right so there you go
你没事吧所以 你去
so that's now you know now you
所以这就是现在你已经知道你
understand pointers simplest can be and
明白最简单的指针可以 和
all you need is page 53 of knr is a
你需要的是 KNR 的53页 是
handy reference all right so let's we'll
便利的参考没事所以让我们
take the last five minutes and I'll show
采取最后五 分钟 ，我会告诉
you some some of the ways you can trip
你有的一些 可以跳闸方式
yourself up when you're accessing memory
你自己了，当你访问内存
okay so first it's a classic scanf bug
好了，首先它是一个典型的错误的scanf
you probably just probably all done this
你可能只是可能都做到了这一点
where you forget to tacit the address of
在那里你忘了默契地址
a variable instead you pass it the
一个变量，而不是给它传递
address so scanf doesn't know where to
地址，以便scanf函数不知道在哪里
put the you know put the put the data ok
把你知道把把数据确定
another another common mistake is to
另一另一个常见的错误是
read uninitialized memory so you can't
读未初始化的内存，所以你不能
really assume that your heap data is
真以为你的堆数据
initialized to zero so here we're we're
初始化为零所以在这里我们是我们
Malachy an array of an int and then
马拉奇int的数组，然后
we're going through and we're doing
我们正在经历，我们正在 做的
we're updating at this vector this Y
我们在这个向量这个 ÿ更新
vector we're reading Y I
矢量我们正在阅读 YI
we're taking Y it's why I equal Y I plus
我们正在采取Ÿ这就是为什么我等于 易加
a IJ times XJ okay so we're using we're
一IJ倍XJ 好了，所以我们使用了我们
assuming that Y that malloc returns
假设是Y确定malloc回报
memory that's all zeros so that'll get
内存是所有 零， 这样 会得到
you
您
it's also easy to allocate the wrong
它也很容易分配错误
sized object so here we want to create
大小的物体所以在这里我们 要创建
an array of end pointers of n pointers
n个指针 的端指针数组
to ends okay and then for each one we
到结束好，然后为每 一个我们
want to allocate em in all right so this
要分配 时间在 没事所以这
work we're creating a two-dimensional
工作中，我们要创建一个二维
array and can you see the mistake which
数组，你可以看到的错误，
which line is buggy this one this one or
该线是越野车这一个这一个或
this one the first one right because we
这其中的第 一个 正确的，因为 我们
really want size events are right so
真想大小事件是对如此
we're we're erroneous incorrectly
我们是我们的错误错误
assuming that intz are the same sizes as
假设intz是尺寸为相同的
pointers this is a classic on this
三分球，这是对这个经典
assumption is true for 32-bit code and
假设是真对32位 代码和
pointers are the same size but it's not
指针的大小相同，但它不是
true for 64-bit and so this is why when
真正的64位，因此这就是为什么当
you when you port when people port
当您端口时， 人口
32-bit code to 64-bit machine a lot of
32位代码，以64位机 很多
times it breaks because they have this
次它打破了，因为他们有这
assumption ok another way it's easy to
假设确定另一种方式可以很容易地
overwrite memory so here we're creating
所以在这里我们要创建覆盖内存
correctly creating this array but then
正确地创建此数组 但随后
when we create each of the each of the
当我们创建各 各的
sub arrays instead of I less than or
子阵列的代替我小于 或
equal to n we're actually we only
等于 n 我们实际上只是我们
created n of these things but we're
创造这些东西n，而是我们
traversing n plus 1 because of this
遍历因为 这款 N加1
lesson are equal so this is a classic
教训是相等的 ，所以这是一个经典
off by one bug ok another another
关闭的一个错误OK另一另一
problem you saw it with the code
问题你的代码看到它
injection attacks from your attack lab
从你的攻击实验室注入攻击
not checking the the size of a buffer so
不检查缓冲区的大小，以便
get get as is a classic example of this
处获得的就是一个典型的 例子
so that will get you into trouble
这样就会让你陷入 困境
another another classic mistake is
另又一个经典的错误是
misunderstanding pointer arithmetic all
误解指针运算全部
right so if you incremental pointer then
正确因此，如果 您增量指针则
it point is incremented by the size of
它点通过的大小递增
the object that pointer points to right
该对象指针指向权
so if you increment an int star by one
所以，如果你通过一个递增的 int 星级
it actually increments it by four
它实际上增加4它
because that's the size of an int
因为这是一个int的大小
got that's a really important
得到了这是一个非常重要的
distinction and so people often so here
区别等人经常因此在这里
it's assuming that incrementing so P is
它假定递增因此P是
the pointer and the programmer here
指针和这里的程序员
assumed that he wants to increment the
假定他要递增
pointer to sort of traverse an array so
指针排序遍历数组所以
he he doesn't understand pointer
他他不明白指针
arithmetic and so to get to the next in
算术等得到下 一个中
increments P by size event okay this
按大小事件增加P 好吧，这
will really increment it by sixteen not
真的会十六个不会递增它
but four okay overriding memory that's a
不过 四和好压倒一切的记忆 ，这是一个
really nasty one and a lot of times this
真是可恶之一，很多 时候，这
can happen if you don't understand the
如果你不明白的可以发生
precedence of the of the operators that
的运营商的优先级是
you're working with so this is a heat
你的工作有 ，所以这 是一个热
not not to kind of heap we've been
不是没有那种堆 ，我们已经
talking about but oh the heap data
谈到但 哦堆数据
structure and this is a this is a
结构，这是 一个，这是一个
function to delete from the heat this
函数从该热删除
actually is from my own code I have to
其实从我自己的代码，我有
admit and so I wanted to leet I want to
承认，所以我想 LEET我想
delete an element I want to delete the
删除元素我要删除
first element of the heap right and then
堆的第一元件右侧，然后
I want to reheat the fly it okay so I
我要重新加热砸进好了，所以我
and then I want to return I want to
然后我想回到我 想
return that so I I get the first element
返回所以II获得的第一个元素
the heap I that the size of the heap or
堆 我该 堆的大小 或
I take the last element and make that
我把最后一个元素，并作出这样的
the first element and and now I want to
第一个元素，而现在我想
decrease the size of the heat because
减少热量，因为大小
this delete operation will delete the
此删除操作将删除
heap size by one so notice here we
通过一个堆大小，以便通知我们在这里
passed size n as a pointer and when this
通过大小n作为一个指针，并且当该
when this function terminate when this
当此功能终止时
function returns size should be updated
函数返回 的大小应 更新
dated size of the pointer the value that
指针的大小过时的值，该值
it points to you should be decremented
它指向你应该递减
okay that's our intent and we do it
还好这是我们的目的 ，我们做
right here with the size minus minus
这里有大小减去减
star so what we want to do is we want to
明星所以我们想要做的是，我们要
dereference size and then decrement that
非关联尺寸，然后递减 该
value but because the unary minus minus
值，但因为一元减减
has higher precedence than then the
具有比则更高的优先级
dereference what we're really doing is
提领我们真正做的是
we're decrementing the pointer and then
我们正在递减的指针，然后
be referencing the value that's
被引用这就是价值
one word less than our size variable all
一个字比我们规模可变减去所有
right so these are nasty and it would
右所以这些都是讨厌的， 它会
have been much cleaner if I just put
已经干净多了，如果我只是把
parentheses around like I intended just
括号周围像我 刚 打算
parentheses star sized parentheses all
括号星 大小 括号所有
right another another way you can mess
正确的另一个另一种方式，你可以乱
up is referencing forgetting the local
最多是引用忘记本地
variables disappear so if you have a
变量消失，所以如果你有一个
function that returns an address of a
函数返回的地址
local variable no good okay no good at
局部变量没有好 还好一点好处
all it might be okay for a while until
所有这可能是好的一段 时间，直到
somebody another function reuses that
有人另一个功能是重用
space it could be a return address it
空间也可以是返回地址是
could be another another functions local
可能是另一个另一个地方的功能
variable another terrible mistake that's
可变另一个可怕的错误那是
a really bad one is freeing a block
一个非常糟糕的 一个被释放的块
multiple time now you know from from
现在您从多个知道时间
your understanding now as malloc that
现在你的理解为 是 的malloc
free actually writes to the heap right
免费其实写到 堆 权
it's coalescing it's changing pointers
它凝聚它的变化指针
it's changing size block sizes so if you
它改变大小的块大小，所以如果你
free a block that's already been freed
免费这已经被释放的块
terrible things will happen another
可怕的事情会发生 另一
thing you can do wrong is to reference a
你可以做错误的事情就是 引用
block you forget that you freed a block
阻止你 忘了，你释放块
and then you reference it so here we
然后 你引用它 因此在这里我们
free of this block X and then we're
免费这个块X的，然后我们
referencing it here another another big
这里引用它的另一个另一大
problem is memory leaks so failing to
问题是内存泄漏所以未能
free block so allocating some block in a
空闲块所以分配的一些块
function and then returning that block
函数，然后返回该块
will stay there forever right because
将永远呆在那里正确的，因为
it's garbage
这是垃圾
okay so there's a there's a number of
好了，有一个有 许多
ways to deal with memory bugs gdb is
方法来处理内存错误是GDB
sometimes good at least it'll tell you
有时好，至少它会告诉你
where a seg fault occurs then you gotta
其中赛格故障发生，然后你得
track down what the right that sort of
追查什么是正确的，诸如此类的
caused that seg fault the best thing you
引起的赛格故障的最好的事情 你
can do but gdb falls down whenever
可以做，但GDB倒下时
you're doing manipulation of complex
你做复杂的操作
data structures
数据结构
it's just simple sort of looking one
它只是简单的排序寻找一个
instruction at a time what you really
同时指令你真的
need to do is identify any complex data
需要做的是找出任何 复杂的数据
structure like a heap for example is
像例如堆结构是
identify invariance for that structure
确定 不变性 为结构
that that data structure should always
该数据结构 要经常
maintain and then you write a function
维护和那么你就写一个函数
that iterates over that structure that
了在该结构 是 迭代
data structure and checks that all those
数据结构，并且检查所有 这些
invariants are true so for example in it
变量是真如此，例如在它
and in allocator one of the invariance
和分配器不变性之一
is that there should be no there should
是不应该有应该有
never be two contiguous free blocks
永远是两个连续的自由块
right so your your consistency checker
右所以你对你的一致性检查
should go through the heat and make sure
应该通过热量，并确保
there's no no contiguous free blocks or
有没有不连续的空闲块或
another invariant is that every free
另一个不变的是，每一个免费
block should be in a free list somewhere
块应该是一个自由的地方名单
right so you would you would you would
右所以你会，你会，你 会
up your consistency checker would scan
您的一致性检查程序将扫描
the heap count the number of free blocks
堆计数的空闲块的数目
and then scan the free list and make
然后扫描空闲列表和使
sure that the number of blocks in the
确保在块数
free list is the same as the number of
空闲列表相同的数
free blocks okay so this idea of a
空闲块好了，所以这个想法的
consistency checker is something you'll
一致性检查的东西，你会
use in your malloc lab but it's
在你的malloc实验室使用，但它的
something it's also something you should
东西它也是东西你 应该
you should use whenever you're updating
每当你更新你应该使用
any kind of complex data structure and
任何种类的复杂的数据结构，并
the and you know about valgrind but the
在你了解 的valgrind 但
great thing about these deep checkers
这些深跳棋伟大的事情
I'm passionate about heat checkers or
我热爱热跳棋或
consistency checkers this is a really
一致性跳棋这是一个非常
powerful thing about them is you write
关于他们强大的东西是 你写的
them to run silently they don't print
他们默默运行不打印
anything unless they find that a
任何东西，除非 他们发现 一个
violation of the invariants if you write
不变量的侵犯，如果你写
your consistency checker like this then
您的 一致性检查这样便
you can use it like a probe so your
你可以使用它 像一个探头，使您的
program crashes so you do if you use
程序崩溃，所以你 如果用 做
this heap checker to do a binary search
这堆检查做二进制搜索
to isolate the cause so you know you put
事业隔离，所以你知道你把
your you put your heap checker here
你把你的堆在这里检查
everything is okay and then later the
一切都没有问题，再后来的
program
程序
Crash's so now you stick the Heep
崩溃的所以现在你坚持的协
checker here and now I crash the Heep
检查器在这里，现在我崩溃 协
checker detection in violation so you
检查发现违反，所以你
know that the problem is somewhere here
知道问题是这里的某个地方
and you can just keep narrowing it down
你可以只保留缩小 下来
so it's just like a probe surgical probe
因此它就像一个探头手术探头
that you can use to to track down bugs
你可以用它来追踪错误
and so that if you do this like it's I
所以，如果你这样做就像是我
don't know how anybody debugs now like
不知道任何人 现在 怎么 样 调试
without this kind of tool
没有这种 工具
okay so that's it for today have a good
好了，这就是它 今天有 一个好
weekend we'll see you on Tuesday
周末，我们会看到你在星期二